software engineering radio episode 75
the new website
[Music]
welcome listeners to a new episode of
software engineering radio actually this
is not a real episode this is just a
little intermediate special episode
where we want to announce our new
website in the next couple of days we
will launch a new website and so first
of all welcome bunt high band has done
most of the work together with a guy
called Frank Hemsworth who is a Drupal
expert the new website is based on
Drupal so we now have a real content
management system running our website
built right yep so and that means we can
have a bunch of benefits for our for our
audience for our users right exactly so
what's different with this new website
so so I think for the users the most
important thing is that we now have the
notion of tagging in our new website so
we have a tag cloud we have different
categories and so it's much easier to
find episodes based on a certain topic
so that means if somebody is interested
in let's say I don't know architecture
then he can basically click on the
architecture word or thingy in the in
the tag cloud and all the episodes
related to architecture are going to be
listed exactly and the same is true for
example for interviews or tech talks or
whatever right ok that's that's very
useful to find new content yeah or well
find existing content I should say
another thing that that has backed me
for a while is that we couldn't easily
add additional pages so if you look at
the old as you radio web well that still
current as a radio web page you'll see
that all kinds of stuff is crammed on
this on this one page so what we can do
now is we can have several sub pages
like obviously one that describes the
team one that describes the legal staff
and and all that stuff so we have much
more freedom in actually building the
website as a combination of many pages
which we couldn't do before and another
really important thing from my point of
view is the new comment system so for
the time being we had only a flat system
of comments so it wasn't really easy to
see if a comment was an answer to
another comment or not and in our new
comments
it is tree based and so you can can see
what is an answer to another comments
one as one now cool I actually didn't
know that but also a mid requires that
people log in and create a user account
with the SU radio website right exactly
that's just to prevent us from having
too much spam on our on our website
right I mean with with the Lipson
standard webpage that the problem was
really that we got like ten or fifteen
spam comments every day so that was
really annoying to moderate all those
away so it means that people who want to
leave comments with se radio they have
to actually log in they have to create
an account and and well I mean you could
argue that this is a bit of pain in the
butt but but I mean you have to log in
to almost every website so I mean why
should we might be much different and we
also really want to build a community
around su radio so I I don't know it's
probably not too much of a pain for you
the users to have to log in there yeah
and on the other side we don't have to
moderate the comments anymore so if you
now paste a comment to our new website
and you'll see it immediately right one
thing is that we did not migrate the old
comments so if you want to see the old
comments the existing comments to the
old episodes you can see them from the
old website which will continue continue
to be available at se radio dot Lipson
dot-com and we'll have a link to that
outside on the new side once the new
side is online right and if somebody
wants to migrate the old comments feel
free and just contact us we were happy
all right so we're always looking for
volunteers but we now also provide the
feed via feed but all right that's right
yeah what's the advantage why do we do
this so on the one hand the load on our
server is much lower now because
Feedburner is doing all the caching and
on the other hand we don't have to care
for all the different RSS feed formats
okay and and in theory and and hopefully
also practically users won't have to
change anything right the URL for the
Feedburner feed will still be SE - radio
dotnet slash RSS exactly it's completely
the same okay currently we still use the
old website when will we do the
migration hope
mid of next week we will be finished
with all the stuff for the website and
then we can do the migration there okay
and as you said I mean we'll just map
the new webpage to the new to the old
URL so NC - radio dotnet will will get
you to the new website until DNS has
updated you'll just get the old website
which is also no problem you also do not
have to change anything about the RSS
feed so is there anything our users need
to be aware of in order to get to the
new website and also Rick continue to
receive the feed I don't think so
everything should be the same if there
are any problems feel free to contact us
and the email address there is team at
se - radio not the usual one exactly the
one we've always used okay and if there
is a problem with a new web page and you
I don't know if it screws up completely
or dies from the enormous load we get
you can always go to su radioed Lipson
comm by the way su radio does Lipson to
come without the - behind the SE it's
just ser a DI or lips and calm and lips
and is li b sy and calm so anything else
bond no I think we're done okay
so listeners this this is another step
in making se radio more professional and
delivering the content in a more
accessible way and clearly communicating
that as your radio is here to stay let
us know what you think and well so much
for today okay thanks bye bye
[Music]
thanks for listening to software
engineering radio if you want to get
more information about software
engineering radio or if you want to give
us feedback please go to our website at
se - radio dot net you can also contact
the team at team at SAE - radio net
although we prefer entries in our
comment system on the website
so other people can see what you think
software engineering radio wants to
thank Henning Poli for the intro and
outro music as well as Lipson for
providing the bandwidth this episode of
se radio as well as all other episodes
is licensed under Creative Commons
license see the software engineering
radio website for details